<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 ###############################################################################
 # Copyright (c) 2008-2012 WalWare/StatET-Project (www.walware.de/goto/statet).
 # All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
 # are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
 # which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
 # http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
 # 
 # Contributors:
 #     Tobias Verbeke - initial implementation
 ###############################################################################
-->
<cheatsheet title="Configure Sweave Document Building">
   <intro>
      <description>
         This cheat sheet shows how to configure all steps in processing an Sweave document into a final output document of your choice.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item title="Open Configuration Dialog" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         Go to <b>Run &gt; External Tools &gt; Open External Tools Dialog... </b> and select
<b>Sweave (R/LaTeX) Document Processing</b>.
<br/><br/>
When the Sweave editor is active, you can also access this dialog via <b>Document &gt; Create / Edit Profiles...</b> on the workbench menu bar.
<br/><br/>
Create a new launch configuration by double-clicking on the selected node or by clicking on the <b>New launch configuration</b> icon. Fill in a <b>Name</b> for this launch configuration.
      </description>
      <command
            confirm="false"
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.externalTools.commands.OpenExternalToolsConfigurations">
      </command>
   </item>
   <item title="1) Sweave Tab" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         Choose either to <b>skip Sweave</b> in the automated building of the document, to specify an <b>Sweave command</b> to be executed or to invoke an <b>R CMD Sweave</b> on the given file. 
<br/><br/>
 Specifying the <b>Sweave command</b> is the most flexible option as it allows the specification of alternative Sweave drivers from add-on packages.
 <br/><br/>
 If  you want to make use of the
<b>R CMD Sweave</b> option, you need to specify the appropriate  <b>R CMD</b> launch configuration. To configure a new one,  use the <b>Create New</b> button next to the option and follow the explanations in the (optional) next step of this cheat sheet.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="1.1) R CMD Sweave Config (optional)" dialog="true" skip="true">
      <description>
         By clicking on the <b>Create New</b> button in the previous step of this cheat sheet, a new launch configuration for <b>R CMD Tools</b> has been created in the External Tools Dialog.
<br/><br/>
One may change the <b>Name</b> of this launch configuration if desired. As can be verified, the <b>Sweave Doc Processing</b> option has been preset in the drop-down menu of R CMD tools in the Main tab.
<br/><br/>
In the R Config tab, one may choose the R configuration that will be used when invoking R CMD Sweave while the Refresh tab allows to automatically refresh resources upon completion of R CMD Sweave.
<br/><br/>
Click on <b>Apply</b> to save the settings and and go back to the Sweave tab of the <b>Sweave (R/LaTeX) Document</b> configuration in which you would like to make use of this newly created R CMD Sweave configuration.
      </description>
      <command
            confirm="false"
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.externalTools.commands.OpenExternalToolsConfigurations">
      </command>
   </item>
   <item title="2) LaTeX Tab" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         The LaTeX tab allows to specify whether you would like the Sweave&apos;d tex file to be opened in an editor, to what output format and using which command you would like to compile this file.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="3) Viewer Tab" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         In the Viewer tab one can choose to <b>disable</b> the preview. Alternatively, it is possible to open the compiled documents using Eclipse&apos;s <b>default editor / viewer</b> for the chosen output files. A third option is to make use of advanced viewer configurations as provided by <b>View LaTeX Document</b>. 
<br/><br/>
<b>View LaTeX Document</b> launch configurations need to be configured
before one can make use of them inside the Viewer tab. To configure a new one, use the <b>Create New</b> button next to the option and follow the explanations in the (optional) next step of this cheat sheet.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="3.1) View LaTeX Document Config (optional)" dialog="true" skip="true">
      <description>
         By clicking on the <b>Create New</b> button in the previous step of this cheat sheet, a new <b>View LaTeX Document</b> launch configuration has been created in the External Tools Dialog.
<br/><br/>
Change the <b>Name</b> of this launch configuration and choose one of the predefined viewers from the drop-down list in the Viewer tab (e.g. acroread).
<br/><br/>
Verify whether the path to the viewer executable is correct and change it if needed via the <b>Change...</b> button.
<br/><br/>
Click on <b>Apply</b> to save the settings and go back to the Viewer tab of the <b>Sweave (R/LaTeX) Document</b> configuration in which you would like to make use of this newly created View LaTeX Document configuration.
      </description>
      <command
            confirm="false"
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.externalTools.commands.OpenExternalToolsConfigurations">
      </command>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
