<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 #=============================================================================#
 # Copyright (c) 2008-2014 Stephan Wahlbrink (WalWare.de) and others.
 # All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
 # are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
 # which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
 # http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
 # 
 # Contributors:
 #     Tobias Verbeke - initial implementation
 #=============================================================================#
-->
<cheatsheet title="Configure and Use the R Package Checker">
   <intro>
      <description>
         This cheat sheet shows how to configure an universal launch configuration check an R package from within Eclipse.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item title="Open Configuration Dialog" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         Go to <b>Run &gt; External Tools &gt; Open External Tools Dialog...</b> and select
<b>R CMD Tools</b>.
<br/><br/>
Create a new launch configuration by double-clicking on the selected node or by clicking on the <b>New launch configuration</b> icon.
<br/><br/>
Fill in a <b>Name</b> for this launch configuration.
      </description>
      <command
            confirm="false"
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.externalTools.commands.OpenExternalToolsConfigurations">
      </command>
   </item>
   <item title="1) Main Tab" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         Choose <b>Add-on Packages: Check</b> from the drop-down menu of commands.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="2) R Config Tab" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         Choose an <b>R Environment</b> you previously configured to be used as R package checker.
 <br/><br/>
 This can either be the R Environment that was set as default for use in the workbench (<b>Workbench Default</b>) or an other R Environment of your choice (<b>Selected Configuration</b>). 
 <br/><br/>
 If you would like to configure a new R environment for the R package checker, you can do so by pushing the <b>Configure...</b> button.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="3) Common Tab" dialog="true" skip="true">
      <description>
         If you would like the R package checker to be listed in the External Tools favorites menu on the workbench toolbar, you can check the External Tools box in the Display in favorites menu.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="Use an R Package Checker" dialog="true" skip="false">
      <description>
         In order to use an R package checker you configured, you need
to first <b>select the package root folder</b> in the Project Explorer view, because the target was configured as &apos;${resource_loc}&apos; (variable for location of currently selected resource in the active view). 
<br/><br/>
If you configured an R package checker, you can make use of
it via <b>Run &gt; External Tools</b> or via the External Tools button on the workbench toolbar. If during configuration you specified to display the R package checker within the favorites, it will be visible directly under the External Tools. To run the given R package checker, click on its name. 
<br/><br/>
 If you did not add it to the favorites during configuration, you need to select <b>Open External Tools Dialog...</b> and click on the configuration you would like to run. Next, click on the <b>Run</b> button to launch the R package checker on your package folder and see whether it passes all tests.
      </description>
      <command
            confirm="false"
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.externalTools.commands.OpenExternalToolsConfigurations">
      </command>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
